<PERSON> <PHONE_NUMBER> | <EMAIL_ADDRESS> | <URL> | Portfolio Page Technical Skills Programming Languages: Java, Python, C/C++, JavaScript, C# Operating Systems: Red Hat Enterprise Linux, Windows, macOS Web Development Languages: <URL> Web API, React, <PERSON>, <LOCATION>, Tailwind Database Environment: MySQL, NoSQL, Oracle, Postgres Tools: Git, <PERSON>, AWS, Google Cloud Platform, <DATE_TIME>, Visual Studio, <PERSON>, Google Colab. Libraries: pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib , Three-js Certification: Data Visualization w python , Python for Data Science Education University of Houston Clear-Lake <LOCATION>, TX Bachelor of Science in Computer Science <DATE_TIME> – Dec 2026 - Related Course-Work: Network Programming, Mobile App Development, Web Development, Data Structure & Algorithm Analysis, Generative AI, Introduction to AI/ML, Big Data. Projects Virasat Technology | React, Tailwind, MongoDB, React-Three, API March 2024 – June 2024 - Built an immersive, high-end interface using React and React-Three-Fiber for 3D visuals. - Improved performance using <URL>mo, lazy loading, and bundle optimization. - Created reusable hooks and utilities to standardize API calls and state management. - Processed and mapped MongoDB JSON data into structured UI components. CyberSwift | React, <PERSON>, Framer-motion, Auth0, Mongodb, nodejs, SocketIO Sep 2024 – Sep 2024 - Developed a 2D RPG-style learning platform with interactive visuals using React + Three.js. - Implemented real-time multiplayer features with <URL>. - Integrated Auth0 for secure authentication and user management. - Built backend services in <DATE_TIME> to support game logic, user data, and progress tracking. Experience Full Stack Engineer Jan 2025 – Present Self-Employed <LOCATION>, <LOCATION> - Designed and built scalable web apps with .NET and C#, focusing on strong server-side logic and modular component design. - Implemented Entity Framework to manage complex data schemas and ensure high-performance interactions with SQL-based backends. - Performed unit/system testing, debugging, and documentation to support stable releases. Full Stack Engineer Jan 2023 – <DATE_TIME> Alter Learning Educational Platform INC Remote - Connected React front-end with Python Flask backend services through custom middleware for consistent headers, request handling, and API reliability. - Developed reusable React components and integrated them into a headless WordPress environment. - Built reusable React components and integrated them into a headless WordPress environment using React-Press. Backend & SEO Optimizer <DATE_TIME> Brilliant Web Presence <LOCATION>, <LOCATION> - Used analytics tools to monitor site performance and ensure accurate reporting. - Supported backend updates, debugging, and performance optimizations across client websites. - Followed structured processes for documentation, quality checks, and data consistency.